<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CodeRuse::Daily chores of life</title>
    <description>Daily chores of life</description>
    <link>http://coderuse.faith/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://coderuse.faith/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 10:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 10:18:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Musical Instruments And Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love to listen to music. I do not understand the grammar of music very much. Only listen what sounds good to my ear. Currently, I’m watching the &lt;em&gt;NCIS&lt;/em&gt; series. There &lt;em&gt;Abby Sciuto&lt;/em&gt;, the allrounder forensic analyst, after disclosing she maintains a &lt;em&gt;NAS&lt;/em&gt; to keep all the music, she usually listens to, asks the war veteran, multiple times purple heart winner &lt;em&gt;Special Agent Gibbs&lt;/em&gt;, how many songs he usually listens. He promptly answers &lt;em&gt;five&lt;/em&gt;. She gasped &lt;em&gt;only five thousand&lt;/em&gt;. He just informatively answered &lt;em&gt;no just five&lt;/em&gt;. Almost the same applies for me. I do not remember the lyrics of a whole song. Only some parts, that strikes. And probably I listen to only twenty to thirty songs if I have to select what I’ve listened to. When I do daily essential domestic chores, generally select a playlist in Gaana and that plays indefinitely until I finish the work. That time, some sound has to linger in the empty rooms. Just that. When my mother lives with me. Then I don’t require to play the Gaana playlist. She talks with me continuously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long time ago, I invested some time to learn vocal music. Later had to suspend that, due to the bad condition of the throat. At that time I used to play Harmonium. A very popular instrument in our country for vocal musicians. Some vocalists also practice with Tanpura. But for the new learners, teachers recommend Harmonium, as it’s hassle free. And gives the correct tone and pitch without any trouble. With Tanpura, one has to configure it properly before starting &lt;em&gt;rewaz&lt;/em&gt;, the practice. So, Tanpura is not generally given before five or six years’ students or serious ones. Harmonium is an interesting instrument. There are a lot of Harmonium playing musicians also. They are quite amazing in crafting tricky tunes in a very fast pace. A lot like pianists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a long time leaving Harmonium started to learn Violin. It’s regarded as the most difficult learn instruments among all. I like the contiguous tone of it. And the melody, that can be made, is amazing. Only it needs a lot of regular practice and patience to play well. And I don’t have the reputation of being a very attentive student. I like to play the violin. But as any other things, my internal mechanism opposes me to have anything as a habit, except bathing and eating. Currently, I’m not practicing it daily. Hope that some day I’ll be able to and some day I’ll be able to play violin nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/09/musical-instruments-and-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/09/musical-instruments-and-me/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Choosing Workstation And Daily Tools</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a little freaky about choosing development environment, to work within. This includes the choice of OS, editor, local or remote etcetera. For some reason, I don’t want to work in local. I don’t know the exact reason behind it. But I like to work in the remote. If the connection sucks, that would be a problem, I know. But India is going towards big bandwidth millennia. So, I depend on the new promises for the long run. In Hyderabad, it’s now 40Mbps up to 150GB (after that 1Mbps) for Rs.641/- per month. I’m not saying it’s cheap. But, compared to the earlier days, like my first internet connection from BSNL &lt;em&gt;Broadband&lt;/em&gt; 1GB for Rs.250/- per month was a nightmare. Every two or three days, the cable got disconnected. And it was really a lucky day if I could get the lineman within 7 days to repair the disconnection. Somehow, I felt at that time that he did not wire the connection properly intentionally. To harass me. I don’t know what his benefit was in it. But I was sure. Eventually, I opted for the local cable operators for the internet connection. That was a &lt;em&gt;unlimited&lt;/em&gt; connection with advertised speed 512Kbps for, as far as I can remember Rs.600/- per month. With this connection, the wire didn’t disconnect every now and then. But, the connection really sucked. I at most got only 450-650Kbps. The only solace was that, great speed in downloading torrents. Around 10Mbps. Actually, the provider hosted some servers to peer for the torrents in the subscriber network. That also got disrupted after some inquiries from the Cyber Crime division of Kolkata police. In my office also the provided internet bandwidth was like a like very tight constipation. Downloading files more than 10MBs was blocked from the proxy. Yes, we had to use a proxy to connect to the internet. YouTube was allowed. But it was better to not watch it. Buffering made the experience real horrifying. I got the first taste of good internet after I came to Hyderabad. The city is good. Peaceful inhabitants. Cool weather. And good internet connection. And it got better. I started with the same plan, that I’m currently using. I started with FUP 10GB. Now it’s 150GB. For a reasonable internet surfer including viewing of reasonable quality videos, 150GB is more than enough. But If anyone likes best quality videos, they have higher plans also. Previously it was the reign of ACT. Now Hathway is also giving &lt;em&gt;unlimited&lt;/em&gt; internet with 50Mbps for only around Rs. 500/- (don’t know their exact packages). But I’m happy with ACT. If I require an unlimited connection, shall think about Hathway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written long completely off-topic. But internet connection is mandatory for working remotely. Currently, I’m working in a windows VM. I’m really liking working in this way. The main advantage is that the workstation does not need to be shut-down unless it becomes very slow. Does not need too much attention to maintaining the hardware, power etc. Anywhere I can just pick up where I left. Surely it has drawbacks. That without the internet, I’ll not be connected. But who nowadays works without the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I’m using &lt;em&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/em&gt; from Microsoft. It’s really a good editor. And with an array of plugins, it has become the default choice for me. And in-built NodeJs debugging is so awesome. Being a front-end developer, I don’t need much. But yes. I’ve installed Visual Studio, SQL Server in this VM. Don’t use them much. But they are there. If I need. I don’t know Java or Python or any compiled languages popular in the OpenSource community. I started my career with &lt;em&gt;C#&lt;/em&gt;. So, still now, got a soft corner for it. Probably if I am able to learn any other language, then will see. I know &lt;em&gt;JavaScript&lt;/em&gt; a little. But in my mind, that language is not for serious stuff. Until &lt;em&gt;JavaScript&lt;/em&gt; runs in a multi-threaded environment successfully, probably this mindset will continue to linger. Currently, I’m liking Golang. But for some reason could not gather enough enthusiasm to learn the language. Probably I’ll learn it in some time. &lt;em&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/em&gt; predicted that &lt;em&gt;Python&lt;/em&gt; is going to be the most popular language by 2019 at-least by the developer count. Actually, Python has acquired this much attention due to data science and machine learning. Python has become the de-facto choice for the new learners of data science and machine learning. And the language is quite easy to learn for new programmers. And in coming years machine learning along with the data science will appear as the most needed in any kind of business. So Python is becoming popular. One thing is there, Python is not compiled. But who cares. Most of the time the machine learning routines runs for days. After all, they are not like web apps. For web apps, I think Golang emerge as the first choice for creating backends. And &lt;em&gt;JavaScript&lt;/em&gt; will continue to reign the client side browser technologies with a monopoly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/08/choosing-workstation-and-daily-tools/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/08/choosing-workstation-and-daily-tools/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Writing Daily Makes Disciplined</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting inspiration for writing is not that easy. Like yesterday I couldn’t write anything. And this &lt;em&gt;100-word-daily-100-days&lt;/em&gt; has just been into even not one week. Today I was reading a post by &lt;a href=&quot;https://writingcooperative.com/the-5-surprising-skills-you-acquire-from-writing-every-single-day-2183080b2fa3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Barry Devret&lt;/a&gt;. There he discussed five benefits of writing every day. But I think benefits are not limited to five only. A lot more. The writer has forgotten to mention one very important one. Discipline. Yes. If we try to write something every day. We have to think over the eternal question, what I should write about. And if we can come up with something for every day, this will become a habit. Habit to become more attentive on our present. This has been discussed as a benefit in the post. Most of the time, we actually think about past or future. Only the happiest people think about the present. It’s true in the deepest sense. I’m advocating for becoming a sage or something, but at least we can be more present in we are doing &lt;em&gt;currently&lt;/em&gt;. This is very important. The first effect would be our work will be much more complete, thoughtful and perhaps more appealing to the audience. In Bengal, there is kind of proverb that, &lt;em&gt;ink, pen, mind writes together&lt;/em&gt;. Don’t take the sentence in its literal meaning. Think about it deeply. To write about something, we need obviously ink and pen (nowadays keyboard and word processor in PC), and the most important player is the &lt;em&gt;mind&lt;/em&gt;. We need to be attentive, observative, careful about what we are writing. In a sense, we have to use our motor functionality as well as neurons. And together they make us more disciplined, observant of the &lt;em&gt;present&lt;/em&gt;. Nowadays we can have an only short span of concentrations. Playing games reduces the span drastically.   If we can engage ourselves within ourselves at least for an hour to write a presentable piece, that would really benefit us not just in five ways, but we can say five folds. Let’s write daily.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/07/writing-daily-makes-disciplined/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/07/writing-daily-makes-disciplined/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy To Implement Search</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last couple of days, trying to implement a search functionality in this website. Now it’s complete. Feeling happy with this success. Implentation of this includes quite a few loose components. A search engine, a NodeJs app as an ACL, Nginx as reverse proxy and the Nginx configured with LetsEncrypt SSL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I tried to look for a simpler and easier solution. Got a few good posts also. The search can be done in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontendcollisionblog.com/javascript/jekyll/tutorial/2015/03/26/getting-started-with-a-search-engine-for-your-site-no-server-required.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;client side&lt;/a&gt; or in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://erudika.com/blog/2016/12/12/Implementing-full-text-search-for-your-static-site/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;server side&lt;/a&gt; or by configuring with &lt;a href=&quot;https://cse.google.com/cse/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Google Search Engine&lt;/a&gt; itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Configuring with Google Search engine is the simplest one. But the search result page redirects to Google’s domain. That’s not a very good experience. But for a quick and dirty fix, it’s quite a promising one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Client side search is a very intuitive one. There are specific solutions for popular static site generators like Hugo, Hexo, Jekyll. This solution is acceptable for sites with preferably not-so-much content. Because it requires to generate a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;json&lt;/code&gt; file with all the posts available in the site. And search is done in the client side by JavaScript. With a large number of posts, even if downloading of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;json&lt;/code&gt; file with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gzip&lt;/code&gt; compression enabled don’t appeared to be a big problem but searching in the client side may result the browser unresponsive for a small duration. I don’t know, whether my site is going to be that big or not, but I prefer to on safe side and implementing the search in the server side, would require at-least some effort, and learning new things. I always like to learn new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For server side searching first I attracted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://paraio.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ParaIO&lt;/a&gt;. That seemed to be full of features also. But while configuring the search, realized I need some sort of ACL. Means I need a server. So, if I require one server, why not use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elastic.co/products/elasticsearch&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Elastic Search&lt;/a&gt; on that server also. By that I will be able to use the same infrastructure in other sites also. Most of my sites are static.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, took onen VPS. Deployed ElasticSearch. ElasticSearch is very light on run and easy to configure. Written one NodeJs app to parse and upload the posts to the ElasticSearch and one for the ACL. Installed Nginx and configured SSL with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-secure-nginx-with-let-s-encrypt-on-ubuntu-16-04&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;LetsEncrypt&lt;/a&gt; and reverse proxy to the ACL. Now the search is available for &lt;a href=&quot;http://coderuse.faith&quot;&gt;faith&lt;/a&gt;. Probably I will write one or multiple posts in my technical blog. But that is the task for future. For today, let’s call it a day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/06/happy-to-implement-search/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/06/happy-to-implement-search/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Busy Days</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some days don’t leave any perceptible impression on our mind, that it has gone, passed by. Today was like this. I could not be myself for the whole day. And it just passed by. It’s not that, I worked very hard today. But somehow it remained unfelt. But I like this kind of days. Nothing new happened. Even didn’t even read an article. Yes, I watched the news for some time. But news content is so cliche that the word &lt;em&gt;cliche&lt;/em&gt; feels like more &lt;em&gt;cliche&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;mundane&lt;/em&gt;. There is no newness in news. Only destruction, corruption, falling humanity. I really doubt the sanity of the mind of the news reader and the journalists nowadays. Really what news they have to cover, then analyze and then read. I’ve seen them analyzing whether a political person has taken the bribe for own party or personal benefit. Bribes are also being categorized currently. What is going to happen to this ill-fated country? Huh.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/05/busy-days/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/05/busy-days/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Childhood Hearthrobs And Others</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mere Pyaari Bindu&lt;/em&gt;. The movie may not be that good in terms of editing, the arrangement of the storyline, but it was enough to bring some of the sweetest memories of my childhood back. I may not have some one like &lt;em&gt;Bindu Shankar Narayana&lt;/em&gt; to love, adore, reminisce memory of. But there were some moments. And the people in those moments made them sweet. There were some aunties like &lt;em&gt;Booby Mashi&lt;/em&gt;, whom we longed for to meet. At that time, it was hard to tell what was, we were longing for, but some unknown feeling engulfed us completely. And there were some girls also. Of same age or younger than us. Girls didn’t give much attention to juniors. There were some girls who loved to criticise our every movement. Whatever that be. Be it newly bought cycle. Or riding on the cycle. Or come out to the playground. May be it was too late. Or too early. Never on time. And by any means she criticised. A long time after watching movies, came to know, those were the first steps of love. Who knew. If I could know, probably didn’t have to be single until the marriage. There were also some studious girls. Always tottering about the class, teachers, text books. It seemed that they were practically in school for all the time. And of-course some girls with superior complexity. Like they know everything from tieing shoelace to how to ride a cycle. I especially felt a sense of danger around these girls. I was always afraid, whether they would start asking any difficult questions. And yes. I think it would be a little difficult to find a Bengali boy, who has not tried to write poems or something. Yes. Almost all of the Bengali boys try to write something in their teenage. And in this regard, I was a little bit famous. Got requests for short poems very often. Some of them were successful, some were not. But it took a little time for us to understand that modern smart girls don’t like emotional short-liners. They are like the show stopper for them. But with these, the memories have become all memorable. And even after a long time, I can clearly remember those new feelings, fear to be exposed and above all the lamest excuses to cover for a friend. Long live childhood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/04/childhood-hearthrobs-and-others/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/04/childhood-hearthrobs-and-others/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Indieweb And Hosting Website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First I had encountered the term &lt;em&gt;IndieWeb&lt;/em&gt; from the website of &lt;a href=&quot;http://anildash.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Anil Dash&lt;/a&gt;. At that time, didn’t give much attention to it. Recently I’ve started this blog. And started looking for some service for syndication of personal sites. There are lot of personal sites with a lot of interesting information. But there is no way to have a collective look at all the publicly available content on some topic. There should be a platform to do this syndication. &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; is a great platform in this regard. But the main problem with &lt;em&gt;Medium&lt;/em&gt; is there is not much option to customize the site. But there is a great feature, that suggests similar posts for a post. And the suggested posts can come from different websites also. Certainly they are doing some ranking of the articles available on their platform to suggest the &lt;em&gt;similar&lt;/em&gt; posts. And this is great. For a reader, this is really an endless horizon. Google search can do this upto certain level. But it can’t capture the mood, context and aspect of an article to find the &lt;em&gt;similar&lt;/em&gt; posts. And above all, Google or any other search engines searches given keywords and ranks the found results. In the process actual &lt;em&gt;similar&lt;/em&gt; posts gets lost from the found results. And ofcourse this should not be in the scope of a general search engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t much know or understand about &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;IndieWeb&lt;/a&gt;. But from their &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/Getting_Started&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;, it appears that they does some sort of syndication. I don’t know but even if they are not suggesting similar posts or syndicates comments, at least they try to encourage in making organised websites in terms of mark-ups at-least. Their &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/IndieMark&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;IndieMark&lt;/a&gt; is quite helpful in this regard. And I think if any website completes at least first five levels of the IndieMark standards, it will be a very good one. And their website is full of information about how to host, where to host, importantly what to host. It’s a fact that, lot of people can’t think of anything to write about. This is a great dilemma to start writing. My principle is that, just write, anything. Whatever you write, you will put some effort to write that. That is required. To become a good writer, you have to write. Continuously. It does not come out in public, how many drafts were discarded by a writer before one gets it’s way to the door of a publication house. Everyone gathers some expertise in their daily life. If all share their part experience, internet will be much more interesting to browse through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy writing blogs. Have a great blog for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/03/indieweb-and-hosting-website/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/03/indieweb-and-hosting-website/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Whom To Believe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today something happened between my parents. Someone self invited to our home and my mom agreed to that. My mom knows very little about this person. Still she agreed to him and asked to come. But my father feared and opposed this and told her to do so. Ultimately my mom also agreed reluctantly and the guest is not coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our ancestral root belongs to East Bengal. And by nature we are very much welcoming. We are not very rich. But one or two guests coming or staying in our home was not a very big deal. I had seen my grandfather actually liked this kind of unknown guests. He used to say that, these increases the connections among people from different regions, sects. But now a days frauds have increased to such a level, we are afraid of inviting someone unknown. Let alone let them stay in our home. The reality series like “Crime Patrol” and “Savdhan India” have made us more cautious, more suspicious. We can not believe any one by his or her face value. It’s very painful. And in the process of filtering out bad ones, probably we are losing some potential good friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a difficult time for our civilisation, society, families. No one believes no one. In the process of elimination, people are getting desparate to find someone to trust. Someone to believe. And this desparation some times put them in gruesome situations, when they become completely puzzled about what to do. Mother kills her own child to protect the identity of her lover. It’s said, a child to a mother is the most close one. It’s true upto certain limits in animals. Some mammals actually eat their child if they are hungry or if the cub interrupts their sexual engagements. But we are human. Expected with some moral and a sense that tells us, we are human. But these kind of crimes directly hurts the basic instinct of beliefs. An infant can believe whom, but it’s mother. Don’t know. This is seriously a difficult time in the face of humanity and civilisation. We need to come out of this. I don’t know how. But we have to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/02/whom-to-believe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/02/whom-to-believe/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Online Privacy And Anonymity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Generally, I don’t read newsletters of hosting companies. But today it was an exception for Dreamhost monthly newsletter. I opened and saw the first section was about their fight against Department Of Justice in the United States. DOJ slapped a search warrant over them to get the visitor details, including their name, photo identity, if exists, email addresses, obviously the owner details of a website, hosted on Dreamhost platform. The site hosts writeups, protest bills, contents to agitate against current president of United States Of America. But visitor details. Really. What the heck!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There should be some limit. And being America a nation supporter of free speech, free expression, this is not at all acceptable. There are other means of law enforcement to subdue any agitation, violence in mass. But this is completely shameful. Being a civilized people there is no way to stop anyone from expressing their principles and ideas or even their grudge over one or many people. And if there are no critics, the ruling party can’t become a good ruling party. And demanding the visitor details is a completely shameless incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, being so agitated, started to search for available means to protect privacy and anonymity of online lives. Seems that there is a huge market for VPN and Proxy(web and socks). Actually, I’m searching for quite a long time. I didn’t like VPN. As it completely wraps the communication of the workstation. This is bad and can raise suspicion. There should be some normal traffic. And the browsing history, emails, chat logs should be private. Unless the user is protesting against a behemoth or doing some heinous crime, I don’t think anonymity is required. But privacy is a must. In another sense actually, privacy comes holding the hand of anonymity. Let’s see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching and reading the privacy and anonymity fanatic websites and posts, came to know that, Finland and Iceland are the freest internet countries. There are almost no internet censorship in those places. It’s hard to get cheap hosting in Iceland. In Finland, there are a lot of hosting providers. But most of their packages are little expensive. Among them, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://creanova.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Creanova&lt;/a&gt;. Their prices are affordable. Minimum VPS package is coming for only Euro 22. But they charge Paypal transaction fees. So, it’s actually Euro 24.06 to be exact. Probably their VPS delivery system is not automated. So, I’ve not still received my VPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to host a SOCKS proxy on the VPS and connect Firefox. So, expected that all the web connections made by Firefox will pass through the SOCKS tunnel. Assuming that the encryption and authentication security is strong enough, that no one can intercept the actual request or TCP/UDP packets until the request goes out of the SOCKS proxy. And every website, I’m visiting will log the IP of the VPS. And I’m mapped to the VPS, so if anyone traces a request, I will be exposed. And the privacy I’m looking for is exposed. Anyone with proper means can track my browsing history, emails, chat logs everything, by simply tapping the gateway of the VPS. So, anonymity is also required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make browsing full anonymous, we need to make use of TOR network. It’s by far most efficient anonymizer available. Now, if my SOCKS server can work through a tor, then everything is achieved. Local ISP’s will not be able to trace HTTP requests. So, local censorships won’t work. And Finland being among the most internet censorship free countries in the world, I’ll be able to breathe in free air, while all my requests will be anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t interact much electronically outside of my work, so email or chat anonymity is not required that much for now. But for them, there are solutions like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whonix.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Whonix&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tails&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://riseup.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Riseup&lt;/a&gt; (but getting an invite for Riseup Red, may be a little tricky). And hopefully, more will come. It’s absurd that, someone will be able to actually take our freedom to roam freely on the internet. There will always be some means to circumvent all the rules and censorships. But, as netizens, we should also maintain our civilized mind in our day-to-day activities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/01/online-privacy-and-anonymity/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/01/online-privacy-and-anonymity/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Salary And Expenses And Other Stuff</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today salary got deposited into the account. And as usual, most of the amount went to soothe the blaze of the credit cards. Every month I’m spending more than 70% of the total amount, I manage to earn in that time period. And it’s getting to an extreme limit. I’m not able to control this by any means. Not being able to concentrate on every aspect of nitty-gritty’s of daily chores, can’t able to think of total spent each time, going to buy something and eventually buy absurd things. Things, not required by me at all. Safe to say, I wouldn’t die without a couple of Swiss knife or various type of inter connecting connectors. But I buy them. Some times I actually forget that I’ve bought something. The shopping spree, when attacks, the excitement, and curiosity is for only that time. A few months back, ordered a bunch of Indian classics like Jataka, Kathasaritsagar etc. Still, I’ve not opened some of the packs. This happens with me. And after the emergence of online shopping in India, this kind of shopping spree attacks are happening quite often for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another out-flow happens due to my affection for eating out. Really I can’t help it. Every day going out somewhere to eat something oily, something not-at-al-healthy, something I would not die without eating and hence making the pocket a little lighter. Currently, my father is here and he cooks in the morning. I come to office having a heavy meal and he packs tiffin for the office. And I don’t feel hungry at all in the noon. But when Ashok asks me out, just line up with him to go somewhere. For some time, I look like a bear in a mirror. I was telling this to him. But as usual, as all other Bengalis, he just said, we live to eat. Typical Bengali philosophy. No way to get out from this mindset. But need to really stop this over eating. Otherwise, I’ll transition into a real bear. And as Madhusudan Dutta said, “Who keeps the light on in the day for a mere joy, they may face a day, when the light will not find it’s path to reach them”. Really it doesn’t look good in a country, where more than 40% of the total population suffering malnutrition. Need to stop this. This is the last day of this month. Let me take a resolution, not to spend if not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/31/salary-and-expenses-and-other-stuff/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/31/salary-and-expenses-and-other-stuff/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
