<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CodeRuse::Daily chores of life</title>
    <description>Daily chores of life</description>
    <link>http://coderuse.faith/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://coderuse.faith/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 05:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 05:22:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Childhood Hearthrobs And Others</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mere Pyaari Bindu&lt;/em&gt;. The movie may not be that good in terms of editing, arrangement of storyline, but it was enough to bring some of the most sweet memories from my childhood back. I may not have some one like &lt;em&gt;Bindu Shankar Narayana&lt;/em&gt; to love, adore, reminisce memory of. But there were some moments. And the people in those moments made them sweet. There were some aunties like &lt;em&gt;Booby Mashi&lt;/em&gt;, whom we longed for to meet. At that time, it was hard to tell what was, we were longing for, but some unknown feeling engulfed us completely. And there were some girls also. Of same age or younger than us. Girls didn’t give much attention to juniors. There were some girls who loved to critisise our every movement. Whatever that be. Be it newly bought cycle. Or riding on the cycle. Or coming out to playground. May be it was too late. Or too early. Never on time. And by any means she critisised. Long time after watching movies, came to know, those were the first steps of love. Who knew. If I could knew, probably didn’t have to be single until the marriage. There were also some studious girls. Always tottering about the class, teachers, text books. It seemed that, they were practically in school for all the time. And of-course some girls with superior complexity. Like they know everything from tieing shoelace to how to ride a cycle. I specially felt a sense of danger around these girls. I was always afraid, whether they would start ask any difficult questions. And yes. I think it would be a little difficult to find a Bengali boy, who has not tried to write poems or something. Yes. Almost all of the Bengali boys try to write something in their teenage. And in this regard, I was a little bit famous. Got requests for short poems very often. Some of them were successful, some were not. But it took a little time for us to understand that modern smart girls don’t like emotional short-liners. They are like show stopper for them. But with these, the memories has become all memorable. And even after long time, I can clearly remember those new feelings, fear to be exposed and above all the lamest excuses to cover for a friend. Long live childhood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/04/childhood-hearthrobs-and-others/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/04/childhood-hearthrobs-and-others/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Indieweb And Hosting Website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First I had encountered the term &lt;em&gt;IndieWeb&lt;/em&gt; from the website of &lt;a href=&quot;http://anildash.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Anil Dash&lt;/a&gt;. At that time, didn’t give much attention to it. Recently I’ve started this blog. And started looking for some service for syndication of personal sites. There are lot of personal sites with a lot of interesting information. But there is no way to have a collective look at all the publicly available content on some topic. There should be a platform to do this syndication. &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; is a great platform in this regard. But the main problem with &lt;em&gt;Medium&lt;/em&gt; is there is not much option to customize the site. But there is a great feature, that suggests similar posts for a post. And the suggested posts can come from different websites also. Certainly they are doing some ranking of the articles available on their platform to suggest the &lt;em&gt;similar&lt;/em&gt; posts. And this is great. For a reader, this is really an endless horizon. Google search can do this upto certain level. But it can’t capture the mood, context and aspect of an article to find the &lt;em&gt;similar&lt;/em&gt; posts. And above all, Google or any other search engines searches given keywords and ranks the found results. In the process actual &lt;em&gt;similar&lt;/em&gt; posts gets lost from the found results. And ofcourse this should not be in the scope of a general search engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t much know or understand about &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;IndieWeb&lt;/a&gt;. But from their &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/Getting_Started&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;, it appears that they does some sort of syndication. I don’t know but even if they are not suggesting similar posts or syndicates comments, at least they try to encourage in making organised websites in terms of mark-ups at-least. Their &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/IndieMark&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;IndieMark&lt;/a&gt; is quite helpful in this regard. And I think if any website completes at least first five levels of the IndieMark standards, it will be a very good one. And their website is full of information about how to host, where to host, importantly what to host. It’s a fact that, lot of people can’t think of anything to write about. This is a great dilemma to start writing. My principle is that, just write, anything. Whatever you write, you will put some effort to write that. That is required. To become a good writer, you have to write. Continuously. It does not come out in public, how many drafts were discarded by a writer before one gets it’s way to the door of a publication house. Everyone gathers some expertise in their daily life. If all share their part experience, internet will be much more interesting to browse through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy writing blogs. Have a great blog for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/03/indieweb-and-hosting-website/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/03/indieweb-and-hosting-website/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Whom To Believe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today something happened between my parents. Someone self invited to our home and my mom agreed to that. My mom knows very little about this person. Still she agreed to him and asked to come. But my father feared and opposed this and told her to do so. Ultimately my mom also agreed reluctantly and the guest is not coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our ancestral root belongs to East Bengal. And by nature we are very much welcoming. We are not very rich. But one or two guests coming or staying in our home was not a very big deal. I had seen my grandfather actually liked this kind of unknown guests. He used to say that, these increases the connections among people from different regions, sects. But now a days frauds have increased to such a level, we are afraid of inviting someone unknown. Let alone let them stay in our home. The reality series like “Crime Patrol” and “Savdhan India” have made us more cautious, more suspicious. We can not believe any one by his or her face value. It’s very painful. And in the process of filtering out bad ones, probably we are losing some potential good friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a difficult time for our civilisation, society, families. No one believes no one. In the process of elimination, people are getting desparate to find someone to trust. Someone to believe. And this desparation some times put them in gruesome situations, when they become completely puzzled about what to do. Mother kills her own child to protect the identity of her lover. It’s said, a child to a mother is the most close one. It’s true upto certain limits in animals. Some mammals actually eat their child if they are hungry or if the cub interrupts their sexual engagements. But we are human. Expected with some moral and a sense that tells us, we are human. But these kind of crimes directly hurts the basic instinct of beliefs. An infant can believe whom, but it’s mother. Don’t know. This is seriously a difficult time in the face of humanity and civilisation. We need to come out of this. I don’t know how. But we have to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/02/whom-to-believe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/02/whom-to-believe/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Online Privacy And Anonymity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Generally, I don’t read newsletters of hosting companies. But today it was an exception for Dreamhost monthly newsletter. I opened and saw the first section was about their fight against Department Of Justice in the United States. DOJ slapped a search warrant over them to get the visitor details, including their name, photo identity, if exists, email addresses, obviously the owner details of a website, hosted on Dreamhost platform. The site hosts writeups, protest bills, contents to agitate against current president of United States Of America. But visitor details. Really. What the heck!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There should be some limit. And being America a nation supporter of free speech, free expression, this is not at all acceptable. There are other means of law enforcement to subdue any agitation, violence in mass. But this is completely shameful. Being a civilized people there is no way to stop anyone from expressing their principles and ideas or even their grudge over one or many people. And if there are no critics, the ruling party can’t become a good ruling party. And demanding the visitor details is a completely shameless incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, being so agitated, started to search for available means to protect privacy and anonymity of online lives. Seems that there is a huge market for VPN and Proxy(web and socks). Actually, I’m searching for quite a long time. I didn’t like VPN. As it completely wraps the communication of the workstation. This is bad and can raise suspicion. There should be some normal traffic. And the browsing history, emails, chat logs should be private. Unless the user is protesting against a behemoth or doing some heinous crime, I don’t think anonymity is required. But privacy is a must. In another sense actually, privacy comes holding the hand of anonymity. Let’s see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching and reading the privacy and anonymity fanatic websites and posts, came to know that, Finland and Iceland are the freest internet countries. There are almost no internet censorship in those places. It’s hard to get cheap hosting in Iceland. In Finland, there are a lot of hosting providers. But most of their packages are little expensive. Among them, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://creanova.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Creanova&lt;/a&gt;. Their prices are affordable. Minimum VPS package is coming for only Euro 22. But they charge Paypal transaction fees. So, it’s actually Euro 24.06 to be exact. Probably their VPS delivery system is not automated. So, I’ve not still received my VPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to host a SOCKS proxy on the VPS and connect Firefox. So, expected that all the web connections made by Firefox will pass through the SOCKS tunnel. Assuming that the encryption and authentication security is strong enough, that no one can intercept the actual request or TCP/UDP packets until the request goes out of the SOCKS proxy. And every website, I’m visiting will log the IP of the VPS. And I’m mapped to the VPS, so if anyone traces a request, I will be exposed. And the privacy I’m looking for is exposed. Anyone with proper means can track my browsing history, emails, chat logs everything, by simply tapping the gateway of the VPS. So, anonymity is also required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make browsing full anonymous, we need to make use of TOR network. It’s by far most efficient anonymizer available. Now, if my SOCKS server can work through a tor, then everything is achieved. Local ISP’s will not be able to trace HTTP requests. So, local censorships won’t work. And Finland being among the most internet censorship free countries in the world, I’ll be able to breathe in free air, while all my requests will be anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t interact much electronically outside of my work, so email or chat anonymity is not required that much for now. But for them, there are solutions like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whonix.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Whonix&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tails&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://riseup.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Riseup&lt;/a&gt; (but getting an invite for Riseup Red, may be a little tricky). And hopefully, more will come. It’s absurd that, someone will be able to actually take our freedom to roam freely on the internet. There will always be some means to circumvent all the rules and censorships. But, as netizens, we should also maintain our civilized mind in our day-to-day activities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/01/online-privacy-and-anonymity/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/01/online-privacy-and-anonymity/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Salary And Expenses And Other Stuff</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today salary got deposited into the account. And as usual, most of the amount went to soothe the blaze of the credit cards. Every month I’m spending more than 70% of the total amount, I manage to earn in that time period. And it’s getting to an extreme limit. I’m not able to control this by any means. Not being able to concentrate on every aspect of nitty-gritty’s of daily chores, can’t able to think of total spent each time, going to buy something and eventually buy absurd things. Things, not required by me at all. Safe to say, I wouldn’t die without a couple of Swiss knife or various type of inter connecting connectors. But I buy them. Some times I actually forget that I’ve bought something. The shopping spree, when attacks, the excitement, and curiosity is for only that time. A few months back, ordered a bunch of Indian classics like Jataka, Kathasaritsagar etc. Still, I’ve not opened some of the packs. This happens with me. And after the emergence of online shopping in India, this kind of shopping spree attacks are happening quite often for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another out-flow happens due to my affection for eating out. Really I can’t help it. Every day going out somewhere to eat something oily, something not-at-al-healthy, something I would not die without eating and hence making the pocket a little lighter. Currently, my father is here and he cooks in the morning. I come to office having a heavy meal and he packs tiffin for the office. And I don’t feel hungry at all in the noon. But when Ashok asks me out, just line up with him to go somewhere. For some time, I look like a bear in a mirror. I was telling this to him. But as usual, as all other Bengalis, he just said, we live to eat. Typical Bengali philosophy. No way to get out from this mindset. But need to really stop this over eating. Otherwise, I’ll transition into a real bear. And as Madhusudan Dutta said, “Who keeps the light on in the day for a mere joy, they may face a day, when the light will not find it’s path to reach them”. Really it doesn’t look good in a country, where more than 40% of the total population suffering malnutrition. Need to stop this. This is the last day of this month. Let me take a resolution, not to eat if not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/31/salary-and-expenses-and-other-stuff/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/31/salary-and-expenses-and-other-stuff/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deploying Faith</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thought that, GitHub pages will be able to handle the Jekyll page generation and deploy will be done automatically. Alas. My assumption came out to be incorrect. GitHub pages’ Jekyll generator works half heartedly only for the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;index&lt;/code&gt; pages. Not for others. So, deleted the old repo and created a CI as in &lt;a href=&quot;http://coderuse.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;coderuse.com&lt;/a&gt; in Bitbucket. Free CI on a need basis. Gives 500 mins for free to build on post check-in hook. Created password token and added in the pipeline variables. This is going to be the first check-in after the set-up. Let’s see if it works. Or will have to do more check-ins changing very little in files. Added the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/arnabdas/4c1e272d1aaff73a916e2c4bf8ee5325&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;random&lt;/a&gt; Git commit messages. So, relieved that don’t have to come with new messages every time. Just &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git random&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; I may be wrong about GitHub pages. In my case the constructed url’s were wrong. But I’ve to check again by creating a site again. For now it’s working perfectly with the Bitbucket pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/30/deploying-faith/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/30/deploying-faith/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dumping Ground And Other Stuff</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a fact that, to feel high, it’s needed to do something substantial. Whatever that may be. Last weekend, I was feeling a bit low. Then on Monday, bought one absurd domain and configured that (which normal person hosts a domain with tld “.faith”!!!). And currently writing for that site. This site is going to be a kind of dumping ground for my mind. I’m more of a thinking type. Always thinking about something. How absurd that may be. But, whatever those are, I’m thinking about them. And if something is churning, it should find some way to out. Otherwise it creates a smelly surrounding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Abhinav mentioned about &lt;a href=&quot;http://penzu.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Penzu&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a online diary simulator. I’ve also created something like a diary, &lt;a href=&quot;http://coderuse.com/memoirable&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;memoirable&lt;/a&gt;. But, diaries again remains with some secrecy in a dark hole. No air or sunlight or bacteria goes there to start the decomposition. That means, no one can see or read what I’ve written. It’s not a requirement, that this should be read by people. In fact I would prefer that, no one should read (what may be a better reason to host a domain, starting with “code”, with tld “.faith”). But there is a potential proximity to be read by another person. This is the ingredient to decompose my thoughts. The mere possibility. That’s required for the stupid mind. I’ve not even configured Disqus. But anyone can contact me. There is a link. But that link is not explicit for wach of the posts. This is the thing. We have to be open about what we are thinking. Otherwise our thoughts would just be within us and create a sting of negative vibes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a reason, old people prefer the toilets outside of the house. We should keep our “dump”ing ground as far as possible. And within the visibility of lot of other people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/29/dumping-ground-and-other-stuff/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/29/dumping-ground-and-other-stuff/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Regarding Motivation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some times comes in life, where I loose the control over it completely. I can’t stir any motivation to do anything interesting, read something new, even to go out. Just I try to finish my daily chores in some way. These are the most dreadful days. I can’t reason the coming of these phases. But they come and recently they are coming very frequently. In these times, generally I watch a TV series. Right now, I’m watching NCIS. Just watching. I’m not even trying to memorise the number of episodes I’ve watched in a season. “Prime” is remembering this for me. And when watching for a long time, sometimes, I can’t understand if I’m awake or sleeping. For some reason/malfunction of “Prime”, if I happen to open any “already watched” episode, those seem to be almost new. Though I can relate to some parts as watched. And this is quite funny actually.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/28/regarding-motivation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/28/regarding-motivation/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
