<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CodeRuse::Daily chores of life</title>
    <description>Daily chores of life</description>
    <link>http://coderuse.faith/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://coderuse.faith/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 14:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 14:05:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Salary And Expenses And Other Stuff</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today salary got deposited into the account. And as usual, most of the amount went to soothe the blaze of the credit cards. Every month I’m spending more than 70% of the total amount, I manage to earn in that time period. And it’s getting to an extreme limit. I’m not able to control this by any means. Not being able to concentrate on every aspect of nitty-gritty’s of daily chores, can’t able to think of total spent each time, going to buy something and eventually buy absurd things. Things, not required by me at all. Safe to say, I wouldn’t die without a couple of Swiss knife or various type of inter connecting connectors. But I buy them. Some times I actually forget that I’ve bought something. The shopping spree, when attacks, the excitement, and curiosity is for only that time. A few months back, ordered a bunch of Indian classics like Jataka, Kathasaritsagar etc. Still, I’ve not opened some of the packs. This happens with me. And after the emergence of online shopping in India, this kind of shopping spree attacks are happening quite often for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another out-flow happens due to my affection for eating out. Really I can’t help it. Every day going out somewhere to eat something oily, something not-at-al-healthy, something I would not die without eating and hence making the pocket a little lighter. Currently, my father is here and he cooks in the morning. I come to office having a heavy meal and he packs tiffin for the office. And I don’t feel hungry at all in the noon. But when Ashok asks me out, just line up with him to go somewhere. For some time, I look like a bear in a mirror. I was telling this to him. But as usual, as all other Bengalis, he just said, we live to eat. Typical Bengali philosophy. No way to get out from this mindset. But need to really stop this over eating. Otherwise, I’ll transition into a real bear. And as Madhusudan Dutta said, “Who keeps the light on in the day for a mere joy, they may face a day, when the light will not find it’s path to reach them”. Really it doesn’t look good in a country, where more than 40% of the total population suffering malnutrition. Need to stop this. This is the last day of this month. Let me take a resolution, not to eat if not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/31/salary-and-expenses-and-other-stuff/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/31/salary-and-expenses-and-other-stuff/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deploying Faith</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thought that, GitHub pages will be able to handle the Jekyll page generation and deploy will be done automatically. Alas. My assumption came out to be incorrect. GitHub pages’ Jekyll generator works half heartedly only for the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;index&lt;/code&gt; pages. Not for others. So, deleted the old repo and created a CI as in &lt;a href=&quot;http://coderuse.com&quot;&gt;coderuse.com&lt;/a&gt; in Bitbucket. Free CI on a need basis. Gives 500 mins for free to build on post check-in hook. Created password token and added in the pipeline variables. This is going to be the first check-in after the set-up. Let’s see if it works. Or will have to do more check-ins changing very little in files. Added the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/arnabdas/4c1e272d1aaff73a916e2c4bf8ee5325&quot;&gt;random&lt;/a&gt; Git commit messages. So, relieved that don’t have to come with new messages every time. Just &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git random&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; I may be wrong about GitHub pages. In my case the constructed url’s were wrong. But I’ve to check again by creating a site again. For now it’s working perfectly with the Bitbucket pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/30/deploying-faith/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/30/deploying-faith/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dumping Ground And Other Stuff</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a fact that, to feel high, it’s needed to do something substantial. Whatever that may be. Last weekend, I was feeling a bit low. Then on Monday, bought one absurd domain and configured that (which normal person hosts a domain with tld “.faith”!!!). And currently writing for that site. This site is going to be a kind of dumping ground for my mind. I’m more of a thinking type. Always thinking about something. How absurd that may be. But, whatever those are, I’m thinking about them. And if something is churning, it should find some way to out. Otherwise it creates a smelly surrounding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Abhinav mentioned about &lt;a href=&quot;http://penzu.com&quot;&gt;Penzu&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a online diary simulator. I’ve also created something like a diary, &lt;a href=&quot;http://coderuse.com/memoirable&quot;&gt;memoirable&lt;/a&gt;. But, diaries again remains with some secrecy in a dark hole. No air or sunlight or bacteria goes there to start the decomposition. That means, no one can see or read what I’ve written. It’s not a requirement, that this should be read by people. In fact I would prefer that, no one should read (what may be a better reason to host a domain, starting with “code”, with tld “.faith”). But there is a potential proximity to be read by another person. This is the ingredient to decompose my thoughts. The mere possibility. That’s required for the stupid mind. I’ve not even configured Disqus. But anyone can contact me. There is a link. But that link is not explicit for wach of the posts. This is the thing. We have to be open about what we are thinking. Otherwise our thoughts would just be within us and create a sting of negative vibes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a reason, old people prefer the toilets outside of the house. We should keep our “dump”ing ground as far as possible. And within the visibility of lot of other people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/29/dumping-ground-and-other-stuff/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/29/dumping-ground-and-other-stuff/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Regarding Motivation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some times comes in life, where I loose the control over it completely. I can’t stir any motivation to do anything interesting, read something new, even to go out. Just I try to finish my daily chores in some way. These are the most dreadful days. I can’t reason the coming of these phases. But they come and recently they are coming very frequently. In these times, generally I watch a TV series. Right now, I’m watching NCIS. Just watching. I’m not even trying to memorise the number of episodes I’ve watched in a season. “Prime” is remembering this for me. And when watching for a long time, sometimes, I can’t understand if I’m awake or sleeping. For some reason/malfunction of “Prime”, if I happen to open any “already watched” episode, those seem to be almost new. Though I can relate to some parts as watched. And this is quite funny actually.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/28/regarding-motivation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/08/28/regarding-motivation/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
