<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CodeRuse::Daily chores of life</title>
    <description>Daily chores of life</description>
    <link>https://coderuse.faith/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://coderuse.faith/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 14:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 14:36:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>As I Am Now</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After realizing the fact, for an unknown reason, a meaningful purpose has completely taken over me. As I used to say, and also written in some of my earlier blogs, even in this site, rather complained about losing motivation. Now, it’s thoroughly gone. Now I know I’ve to continue at least for the next 24/25 years in order to support the child. It’s actually amazing to have someone to get going. May be I can also make progress in some of the streams I’ve been thinking about for a long time. But again it’s very unfortunate that I can’t go outside the influence of my family. Family is required. But one should be ready to work on his/her own. Then the opportunity of actual improvement can be envisaged. Nothing should influence a person so much, that may sketch the path of life. I can’t deny the requirement for insiparion to go on in tough situations and I got one. That’s the good news after all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://coderuse.faith/2018/07/06/as-I-am-now/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://coderuse.faith/2018/07/06/as-I-am-now/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vote, Summer, Oil Price And As We Are</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are vote survivors. Yes. We were able to “sustain” our life during last vote in West Bengal and just continuing. Not without worrying about some very “burning” issues, obviously increment in oil price is one among them. But still continuing life of weaklings as we are, keeping our breath “afloat”. We were supposed to cast vote for candidates of our choice in the elections. But in reality we saw that, there are no personal choice in the matter of selecting candidates. There are influence of different interests and in some cases probably clan level decision. And moreover the result, the selected candidates, in most of the cases are the result of rigging the balot box, spreading terror among voters by goons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are afraid by so much death. Unofficial count of death during last panchayat poll in West Bengal is more than 30. Leave 30, why even one. I was thinking about this. Why so many people are dead. Are all of them, so much inspired by their leader, that they just fought until they died. By hearing the comments made by the current leaders, ruling and opposition, the actions taken by them, I doubt that it’s at all possible to be this much inspired by these lying machines. If they were not inspired, then why? I think for some winning this “contest” is directly related to their job and earning. And for that reason the clash is this big and this much demanding. There may be other reasons. But this is in my opinion is the most propelling one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last few days, oil price is increasing. Previously, government subsidy kept an buffer over the increment of the same in international market. Now, the government has passed a bill to not give the subsidy. So the oil price is increasing with the rise of the price in international market. As a result the price is really high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now an example of thought process of a rougue politician’s mind. In the last month, there was Assembly election in Karnataka. After the declaration of the election result only, the price of the oil is increasing per day. Now the oposition in Loksabha are alleging the ruling party that, to influence the common mindset, central has not increased the oil price until the end of the election. Once it’s done, it gave nod to the oil companies for the increment. I don’t know what actually happened. But it’s amazing that someone can think so narrow mindedly and so vindictive-ly. And also if central had done this intentionally. It’s so rougue. And so scrupulous. This should not happen. Ruling party should be nutral and be above all the idiosyncrasies like this. They have already got most of the seats in the assembly, though they could not make the board, but the trend was in their favor. Then why did they need such a low level manoeuvre. Don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all of this, we are common people. And we have to survive, vote after vote. With the increase of oil price, increase of price daily needs. But we don’t want the untimely deaths of anyone. Really we don’t want to see anymore lose of valuable life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://coderuse.faith/2018/06/03/vote-summer-oil-price-and-as-we-are/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://coderuse.faith/2018/06/03/vote-summer-oil-price-and-as-we-are/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Life As A Stream</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Time is like a river. We are flowing in that. Sometimes another stream comes and meets us. But unlike an actual river, they don’t dissolve or melt away into us, rather they flow alongside. And may be at a later point in time, they cleave themselves to take another route. But the time, we are together, mostly we both benefit exchange of views, helping each other and mostly being harmony. Yes, the last one is the most important, be connected, be one with other. This is required to flow. There may come some rocks, some perils of our stream are blocked. But with someone, in unison, we can flow over the rocks, boulders or fear of being obstructed. Alone we may not, but together we can come along any hindrance if the partner is right. Yes. This is another important aspect. Choosing the right or appropriate partner to flow contiguously. If we are not wise enough to choose the right one, the other flow may water down our own flow. Then the harmony will be missing. We will not be able to benefit from being together. So, we have to be cautious in whom we are choosing to flow along with us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://coderuse.faith/2018/04/09/life-as-a-stream/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://coderuse.faith/2018/04/09/life-as-a-stream/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy New Year</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Year passes by. Passes by the time, I want to believe in. The very question of whether to continue or not, remains with a glowy aura around. In despair, at the ends of paths, whenever I think of betraying the natural course of life, a wall of very rigid sense comes in the way to freedom. A great author once said, it’s very difficult to walk here for those, who have even a feeling of ‘there’. Didn’t think of much, when was not ready. But now it feels truth at it’s best. Each day passes as the rolling of tightly swindled rope around a weary body. There is no energy remaining to initiate the exit. So the only course is to think of ‘there’ and just continue. Just continue. Nothing else. Like the travellers, almost at the end of their destination, the last point is seen at the corner of the road. Accumulating the last drops of hope by seeing the destination at a distance. And with the hope, just walking, continuing the natural course of life. What else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://coderuse.faith/2018/01/02/happy-new-year/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://coderuse.faith/2018/01/02/happy-new-year/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Being Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Year after year goes by. Growing older each year by one year. I am thankful a lot of people, that they are letting me to grow up. Really. I should be thankful and I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I ponder over one question, what if I’m not there. Not here. Anywhere. Nowhere. What would happen? Would anybody notice my absense? Is there anyone, who would actually feel the void of me not around anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve my parents. They are going to feel the void. Yes. They will. For the first somedays, it would be an insufferable pain. After that, presumably, they will try to cope up with the situation. And if they are unlucky enough to live a long life, they will learn to live without me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, is it right for me. Obviously not. They looked after me, when I was weak, when I was sick. Now, I don’t live with them, but they have the assurance that, I’m there and I’m for them when they need. Even if they don’t need, I’m there to be with them at least for sometime. This is what they look for, longing for, throughout the whole year. And I’m in no place to be &lt;em&gt;nowhere&lt;/em&gt; for them. I’ve to be always &lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt; for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be selfish. Be what you are. Feel what you are. I’m lucky that, I’ve a family. Even if you don’t have a family, be for yourself. You should long for yourself. Actually that is more liberating. There are no obligations for you. So, you can do whatever you want. Whatever. You have the liberty to come up with your real self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very few gets the chance to be &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;. Whatever you are. Whatever your situation may be. You are &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;. This is a blessing. So be &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;. Be happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://coderuse.faith/2017/11/24/being-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://coderuse.faith/2017/11/24/being-me/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anonymous Shakespear</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was watching “Anonymous”. Before this never knew of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oxfordian_theory_of_Shakespeare_authorship&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Oxfordian Theory Of Shakespear Authorship&lt;/a&gt;. And truthfully, this play of mucking the name “Shakespear” is quite distasteful and proofs are mostly circumstantial. No doubt the earlier works, attributed to Shakespear are much more rich in literary excellence than the later ones. But we should not forget the fact that, Shakespear became the most popular, successful and hence one of the busiest playwrights of his time. Great work needs a great deal of time and patience. I think the downfall of quality and richness of creations are expected, as we see in the works of literary geniuses in modern days also. I’ve found only two facts that may go against the authenticity as the writer for the man known as Shakespear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that, there are no manuscripts written by Shakespear, may happen if the creator dictates his creation to scriptors and of-course at the same time, more than one copy can be made, and that may be required. He was a busy man. So, it was really convenient. But earlier days. Shouldn’t at least some drafts or final copies for the earlier creations be found? Whatever may be the fact, it’s hard to believe, that a playwright won’t relish writing his own piece for a single time. And if we want to believe that, every time he used to let someone copy his manuscript before giving someone, then also at least some specimen should there be to read. Afterall it’s only 400 years ago. And belongings of someone of his stature and popularity could have been well preserved by at-least the fans, if not by him. And also it’s hard to believe, such a romantic individual couldn’t scratch at least some words to give his fans, friends or well-wishers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the second doubt is, the plays exhibit an immense knowledge about courts, not only of England but also French and Italia at that time, from the author. And there is no such evidence that can prove Shakespear’s adjacency to such an elite society in his life, to equip him to depict the orders and atmosphere with such an elegance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are two discrepancies I’ve found to be hard to believe. Otherwise, in a way, this kind of discussions are of no use. For a long time those plays, poems, literary works are known to be written by Shakespear. Even if they are not actually, they are by common beliefs. And Edward De Vere was not just a vagrant to be imposed upon. Most of the plays were published in his lifetime. If he suppressed his identity, we should respect him. And try not to mucker a name, worshipped by all, who knows at least the name of the language “English” and disrespect the wish of a noble man.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://coderuse.faith/2017/10/30/anonymous-shakespear/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://coderuse.faith/2017/10/30/anonymous-shakespear/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Path, Journey et all</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After all, we are alone. Some are by choice. Some are by the situation. And few, very few feel they are not alone. Though by nature and basic instinct of human beings, we are alone. Alone by our own side. More we go, more we travel we become alone. So the first lesson of being a sage is being alone. Buddhists say monks should be alone like a rhinoceros. Because they have to travel a lot. So less the baggage better they can travel. Be in the company, but don’t bear the bags for the company. Love, care, sympathy should be for everyone equally. There would be no expectations as there would be no one special. And most of the fear, most of the conflicts would go away. Long long miles apart. And of course, we have to pack our backpacks light. Otherwise, we would become selfish. If we are not willing to carry any one’s bag, we should not also make a bag of our own. But we have to continue our journey. So we need some essentials. But we have to choose them very carefully. Not a single item except the real necessities. At the first time, everyone gets confused regarding what to choose and what not to. So we need guidance. We need teachers. We have to be very careful in choosing the teacher. The teachers are those who have already traveled some distance and know the perils of the route so that they can warn us. But we have to see whether the goal of the route taken by the teacher have some similarity to the goal we want to see for ourselves. Meeting a good teacher is very difficult. And a lot of potentials actually gets wasted due to the teachers and also a lot bloom to the perfection for them. The Same road may not be suitable for everyone. And it has always been observed that being in the vicinity of the most crowded road is the safest. After all the destination is same for all. Only the differences are on the routes we take to reach the destination. If we can believe on a route, that will take to the destination. Some delay may occur. Determination is the only key to reach. And as a matter of speak, there is no end in the travel. Beware of those, who say they have reached. No one can stop the journey as there are always new things to learn, new places to go, new ideas to try. Saturation, satisfaction is the death of a traveler. Enjoy the joy of making the journey. No matter what we have to continue. Continuity is life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://coderuse.faith/2017/10/17/journey-of-life/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://coderuse.faith/2017/10/17/journey-of-life/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best Days In My Life</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just now watched three movies back to back &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0815236/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;She’s Out Of My League&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;www.imdb.com/title/tt0452625&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Good Luck Chuck&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1625346/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Young Adult&lt;/a&gt;. Man, what a depth she has. Charliz Theron. She is the most attractive, most sensitive, most empathetic. She is the best among three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though my school life was not that memorable. But those days feels very good. I never dated in school. In college. Not even in University. But the school and University both feels good. Both of the time didn’t feel the peer pressure for getting someone. And in fact University was great. Best days of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can completely relate with Marvis Gary. Completely. Though I’m not that successful as her. But both of us has spend their most memorable days. Best days are gone. Long long gone. But still we are looking for some days in future to make them part of our best ones. Though I’m not sure how. But there is no harm in wishing some good days for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life I’m coming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://coderuse.faith/2017/10/16/best-days/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://coderuse.faith/2017/10/16/best-days/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NCIS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NCIS_(TV_series)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;NCIS&lt;/a&gt;. It’s just not a TV series, it’s a kind of journey of life. It’s adherence to pure principles of life makes it unique among the likes. The characters with their evolution through each episodes have been remarkably sketched with great care. Apart from exerting extraordinary efforts towards their duty, they are human, infact too much. When as a viewer we expect something heroic, they exhibit painstakingly common persona while doing their job. So they fail, they make mistakes. But they can’t imagine to leave behind a fellow traveler, whether be a marine or a most commoner. Everyone gets chance, importance. The way they should. It’s no miracle, it’s the most watched criminal investigation series in USA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://coderuse.faith/2017/10/15/ncis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://coderuse.faith/2017/10/15/ncis/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Entry</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having the full wish to write every day, is not at all, all to write everyday. It takes a determination of different level. So after the start of writing spree, it has been quite a long time since the last entry. And a couple of entries are also back dated. At that time, it almost felt like doing pending homework. So discontinued. Writing doesn’t come as homework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the last entry lot of things happened. Taken a few small projects personally. All of them discontinued due to lack of enthusiasm for running for a small duration. Some of the efforts included get up early and doing exercises also. Joke apart, personal projects, any type of project needs a lot of determination. No doubt. And the individuals, who finish, suppose open source or say runs some kind of common interest groups, are really respectable, admirable. Just now came across a post in Medium about starting. Good to read. Nothing new. But nicely arranged. &lt;a href=&quot;https://artplusmarketing.com/starting-things-is-scary-3755079bd8cf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Starting things is scary.”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Went to Kolkata during Durga puja. Saw a lot of familiar faces. Actually seeing someone after a long time feels somewhat warm. Can’t describe exactly. But warm. Even the person whom I didn’t like in the past, seems, what I can say, ‘lukewarm’?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://coderuse.faith/2017/10/14/new-entry/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://coderuse.faith/2017/10/14/new-entry/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
