<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CodeRuse::Daily chores of life</title>
    <description>Daily chores of life</description>
    <link>http://coderuse.faith/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://coderuse.faith/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 18:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 18:09:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Being Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Year after year goes by. Growing older each year by one year. I am thankful a lot of people, that they are letting me to grow up. Really. I should be thankful and I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I ponder over one question, what if I’m not there. Not here. Anywhere. Nowhere. What would happen? Would anybody notice my absense? Is there anyone, who would actually feel the void of me not around anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve my parents. They are going to feel the void. Yes. They will. For the first somedays, it would be an insufferable pain. After that, presumably, they will try to cope up with the situation. And if they are unlucky enough to live a long life, they will learn to live without me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, is it right for me. Obviously not. They looked after me, when I was weak, when I was sick. Now, I don’t live with them, but they have the assurance that, I’m there and I’m for them when they need. Even if they don’t need, I’m there to be with them at least for sometime. This is what they look for, longing for, throughout the whole year. And I’m in no place to be &lt;em&gt;nowhere&lt;/em&gt; for them. I’ve to be always &lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt; for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be selfish. Be what you are. Feel what you are. I’m lucky that, I’ve a family. Even if you don’t have a family, be for yourself. You should long for yourself. Actually that is more liberating. There are no obligations for you. So, you can do whatever you want. Whatever. You have the liberty to come up with your real self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very few gets the chance to be &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;. Whatever you are. Whatever your situation may be. You are &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;. This is a blessing. So be &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;. Be happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/11/24/being-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/11/24/being-me/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anonymous Shakespear</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was watching “Anonymous”. Before this never knew of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oxfordian_theory_of_Shakespeare_authorship&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Oxfordian Theory Of Shakespear Authorship&lt;/a&gt;. And truthfully, this play of mucking the name “Shakespear” is quite distasteful and proofs are mostly circumstantial. No doubt the earlier works, attributed to Shakespear are much more rich in literary excellence than the later ones. But we should not forget the fact that, Shakespear became the most popular, successful and hence one of the busiest playwrights of his time. Great work needs a great deal of time and patience. I think the downfall of quality and richness of creations are expected, as we see in the works of literary geniuses in modern days also. I’ve found only two facts that may go against the authenticity as the writer for the man known as Shakespear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that, there are no manuscripts written by Shakespear, may happen if the creator dictates his creation to scriptors and of-course at the same time, more than one copy can be made, and that may be required. He was a busy man. So, it was really convenient. But earlier days. Shouldn’t at least some drafts or final copies for the earlier creations be found? Whatever may be the fact, it’s hard to believe, that a playwright won’t relish writing his own piece for a single time. And if we want to believe that, every time he used to let someone copy his manuscript before giving someone, then also at least some specimen should there be to read. Afterall it’s only 400 years ago. And belongings of someone of his stature and popularity could have been well preserved by at-least the fans, if not by him. And also it’s hard to believe, such a romantic individual couldn’t scratch at least some words to give his fans, friends or well-wishers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the second doubt is, the plays exhibit an immense knowledge about courts, not only of England but also French and Italia at that time, from the author. And there is no such evidence that can prove Shakespear’s adjacency to such an elite society in his life, to equip him to depict the orders and atmosphere with such an elegance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are two discrepancies I’ve found to be hard to believe. Otherwise, in a way, this kind of discussions are of no use. For a long time those plays, poems, literary works are known to be written by Shakespear. Even if they are not actually, they are by common beliefs. And Edward De Vere was not just a vagrant to be imposed upon. Most of the plays were published in his lifetime. If he suppressed his identity, we should respect him. And try not to mucker a name, worshipped by all, who knows at least the name of the language “English” and disrespect the wish of a noble man.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/10/30/anonymous-shakespear/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/10/30/anonymous-shakespear/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Path, Journey et all</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After all, we are alone. Some are by choice. Some are by the situation. And few, very few feel they are not alone. Though by nature and basic instinct of human beings, we are alone. Alone by our own side. More we go, more we travel we become alone. So the first lesson of being a sage is being alone. Buddhists say monks should be alone like a rhinoceros. Because they have to travel a lot. So less the baggage better they can travel. Be in the company, but don’t bear the bags for the company. Love, care, sympathy should be for everyone equally. There would be no expectations as there would be no one special. And most of the fear, most of the conflicts would go away. Long long miles apart. And of course, we have to pack our backpacks light. Otherwise, we would become selfish. If we are not willing to carry any one’s bag, we should not also make a bag of our own. But we have to continue our journey. So we need some essentials. But we have to choose them very carefully. Not a single item except the real necessities. At the first time, everyone gets confused regarding what to choose and what not to. So we need guidance. We need teachers. We have to be very careful in choosing the teacher. The teachers are those who have already traveled some distance and know the perils of the route so that they can warn us. But we have to see whether the goal of the route taken by the teacher have some similarity to the goal we want to see for ourselves. Meeting a good teacher is very difficult. And a lot of potentials actually gets wasted due to the teachers and also a lot bloom to the perfection for them. The Same road may not be suitable for everyone. And it has always been observed that being in the vicinity of the most crowded road is the safest. After all the destination is same for all. Only the differences are on the routes we take to reach the destination. If we can believe on a route, that will take to the destination. Some delay may occur. Determination is the only key to reach. And as a matter of speak, there is no end in the travel. Beware of those, who say they have reached. No one can stop the journey as there are always new things to learn, new places to go, new ideas to try. Saturation, satisfaction is the death of a traveler. Enjoy the joy of making the journey. No matter what we have to continue. Continuity is life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/10/17/journey-of-life/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/10/17/journey-of-life/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best Days In My Life</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just now watched three movies back to back &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0815236/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;She’s Out Of My League&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;www.imdb.com/title/tt0452625&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Good Luck Chuck&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1625346/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Young Adult&lt;/a&gt;. Man, what a depth she has. Charliz Theron. She is the most attractive, most sensitive, most empathetic. She is the best among three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though my school life was not that memorable. But those days feels very good. I never dated in school. In college. Not even in University. But the school and University both feels good. Both of the time didn’t feel the peer pressure for getting someone. And in fact University was great. Best days of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can completely relate with Marvis Gary. Completely. Though I’m not that successful as her. But both of us has spend their most memorable days. Best days are gone. Long long gone. But still we are looking for some days in future to make them part of our best ones. Though I’m not sure how. But there is no harm in wishing some good days for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life I’m coming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/10/16/best-days/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/10/16/best-days/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NCIS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NCIS_(TV_series)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;NCIS&lt;/a&gt;. It’s just not a TV series, it’s a kind of journey of life. It’s adherence to pure principles of life makes it unique among the likes. The characters with their evolution through each episodes have been remarkably sketched with great care. Apart from exerting extraordinary efforts towards their duty, they are human, infact too much. When as a viewer we expect something heroic, they exhibit painstakingly common persona while doing their job. So they fail, they make mistakes. But they can’t imagine to leave behind a fellow traveler, whether be a marine or a most commoner. Everyone gets chance, importance. The way they should. It’s no miracle, it’s the most watched criminal investigation series in USA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/10/15/ncis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/10/15/ncis/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Entry</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having the full wish to write every day, is not at all, all to write everyday. It takes a determination of different level. So after the start of writing spree, it has been quite a long time since the last entry. And a couple of entries are also back dated. At that time, it almost felt like doing pending homework. So discontinued. Writing doesn’t come as homework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the last entry lot of things happened. Taken a few small projects personally. All of them discontinued due to lack of enthusiasm for running for a small duration. Some of the efforts included get up early and doing exercises also. Joke apart, personal projects, any type of project needs a lot of determination. No doubt. And the individuals, who finish, suppose open source or say runs some kind of common interest groups, are really respectable, admirable. Just now came across a post in Medium about starting. Good to read. Nothing new. But nicely arranged. &lt;a href=&quot;https://artplusmarketing.com/starting-things-is-scary-3755079bd8cf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Starting things is scary.”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Went to Kolkata during Durga puja. Saw a lot of familiar faces. Actually seeing someone after a long time feels somewhat warm. Can’t describe exactly. But warm. Even the person whom I didn’t like in the past, seems, what I can say, ‘lukewarm’?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/10/14/new-entry/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/10/14/new-entry/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>About Love</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I’m quite curious about a topic, that has always intrigued people generations after generations, irrespective of their creed, beliefs whatever. &lt;em&gt;Love&lt;/em&gt;. One of the very few words which has it’s equivalent in all languages. And as far as have seen, the &lt;em&gt;Love&lt;/em&gt; word in every languages sounds very sweet. And we can’t deny whatever macabre acts have hitherto been done in the name of &lt;em&gt;Love&lt;/em&gt;, it has always delighted anyone, in the mere prospect of get some. Really don’t know, what is love. But I love to be in the feelings, that have been developed over time for this word. Everyone has different feelings for this word. And what I love, you may not. So, what for me is a lovely atmosphere, you may laugh or joke on. But you can’t deny that is not inducing some sort of soothing feelings. Yes. Though each one of us bears different feelings for the same word, those feelings have a common base. Common ground, from which they all have been constructed brick by brick. People are very choosy in filling the box of feelings for love. In that common ground we can all gather together to be united with others. To be one. There would be no difference in beliefs, in doings. I really doubt, the thoughts of falling in love for the first time in a girl from India is different from one from Israel or US or around the world. May be the context, country, language, education, society is different, but first feelings are the last feelings, lasts forever in every consequent falling in love, breaking relationship and when going to die. And people don’t feel content if the first feeling does not felt in any later relations. Lot of people makes multiple relations, probably they just search for their first love, the depth, the unknown feelings in heart, mind, body. Some controls themselves. But every one likes to feel the first love always. In Indian scriptures for sages, it has been advised to channel the &lt;em&gt;Love&lt;/em&gt; for nature, food and bhajan(prayer). Even the iron clad mind of a moralistic saint couldn’t deny the need of &lt;em&gt;Love&lt;/em&gt;. And some sects actually try to feel love in the love of &lt;em&gt;Purush&lt;/em&gt;, God and &lt;em&gt;Prakriti&lt;/em&gt;, all else, symbolised as &lt;em&gt;Krshna&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Radha&lt;/em&gt;, the eternal love affair between two teens a long time ago. Sages through generations have thrilled, have been engulfed in the purest &lt;em&gt;Love&lt;/em&gt; affair written ever. In it’s purest form, body can’t be differenciated from &lt;em&gt;mind&lt;/em&gt;. So true &lt;em&gt;Love&lt;/em&gt; does not discard body, rather embraces it to be more close and united. Today don’t want to discuss about the consequences of it. But we should confine ourselves in our humane nature, to unify with every one else, to expand the horizon, to embrace &lt;em&gt;Prakriti&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/11/about-love/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/11/about-love/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brainstorming 'N Etc...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In software companies, the term &lt;em&gt;brainstorming&lt;/em&gt; is quite popular, especially to the freshers, aka fresh out of engineering college. But before starting this topis, I should warn you that I posses a very negative view towards the &lt;em&gt;activities&lt;/em&gt;, that are generally done for this &lt;em&gt;act&lt;/em&gt; of &lt;em&gt;brainstorming&lt;/em&gt;. Yes, this is an &lt;em&gt;act&lt;/em&gt;ing, atleast most of the time. Okay let’s try to put up a description of &lt;em&gt;brainstorming&lt;/em&gt;. First rule of &lt;em&gt;brainstorming&lt;/em&gt;, there has to be more than two people in that session, actually more the merrier. Second, there has to be one separate room, in which this &lt;em&gt;act&lt;/em&gt; to be carried on. Third, the topic should be as much abstract as possible, so that the &lt;em&gt;actors&lt;/em&gt; should be able to kill some time to decide the exact outcome of it. I’ve never seen any of this kind of sessions has ended in less than one hour. It goes on and goes on. And long time, some senior like project lead or manager chucks in to the room and just puzzle all the hitherto understood concepts. And then again the session starts from &lt;em&gt;scratch&lt;/em&gt; again. In the services sector of software industry this is another sacred term. We are like the &lt;em&gt;carpenters&lt;/em&gt;. Only want to do, feel happy to do a project from &lt;em&gt;scratch&lt;/em&gt;. Whatever solution or opensource project there be, we always pitch for start from &lt;em&gt;scratch&lt;/em&gt;. Bigger the organisation, more the rush for it. There is a business part of it also, but it appeals most to the developers. They don’t need to learn anything, don’t need to see any existing solution. Just &lt;em&gt;brainstorm&lt;/em&gt; over the requirement and do something, release and then make the customer to opt for the &lt;em&gt;maintainance period&lt;/em&gt;. Customer has to take the maintainance to get rid of the bugs in the &lt;em&gt;from-scratch&lt;/em&gt; application. This is one sort of &lt;em&gt;brainstorming&lt;/em&gt; needed to be done for client requirement. Another is for the free people, aka people who are in bench. The poor fellows have to perform, have to do some extra &lt;em&gt;miracle&lt;/em&gt;, so they have to chime in any bogus ideas of &lt;em&gt;managers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/10/brainstorming-n-etc/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/10/brainstorming-n-etc/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Musical Instruments And Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love to listen to music. I do not understand the grammar of music very much. Only listen what sounds good to my ear. Currently, I’m watching the &lt;em&gt;NCIS&lt;/em&gt; series. There &lt;em&gt;Abby Sciuto&lt;/em&gt;, the allrounder forensic analyst, after disclosing she maintains a &lt;em&gt;NAS&lt;/em&gt; to keep all the music, she usually listens to, asks the war veteran, multiple times purple heart winner &lt;em&gt;Special Agent Gibbs&lt;/em&gt;, how many songs he usually listens. He promptly answers &lt;em&gt;five&lt;/em&gt;. She gasped &lt;em&gt;only five thousand&lt;/em&gt;. He just informatively answered &lt;em&gt;no just five&lt;/em&gt;. Almost the same applies for me. I do not remember the lyrics of a whole song. Only some parts, that strikes. And probably I listen to only twenty to thirty songs if I have to select what I’ve listened to. When I do daily essential domestic chores, generally select a playlist in Gaana and that plays indefinitely until I finish the work. That time, some sound has to linger in the empty rooms. Just that. When my mother lives with me. Then I don’t require to play the Gaana playlist. She talks with me continuously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long time ago, I invested some time to learn vocal music. Later had to suspend that, due to the bad condition of the throat. At that time I used to play Harmonium. A very popular instrument in our country for vocal musicians. Some vocalists also practice with Tanpura. But for the new learners, teachers recommend Harmonium, as it’s hassle free. And gives the correct tone and pitch without any trouble. With Tanpura, one has to configure it properly before starting &lt;em&gt;rewaz&lt;/em&gt;, the practice. So, Tanpura is not generally given before five or six years’ students or serious ones. Harmonium is an interesting instrument. There are a lot of Harmonium playing musicians also. They are quite amazing in crafting tricky tunes in a very fast pace. A lot like pianists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a long time leaving Harmonium started to learn Violin. It’s regarded as the most difficult learn instruments among all. I like the contiguous tone of it. And the melody, that can be made, is amazing. Only it needs a lot of regular practice and patience to play well. And I don’t have the reputation of being a very attentive student. I like to play the violin. But as any other things, my internal mechanism opposes me to have anything as a habit, except bathing and eating. Currently, I’m not practicing it daily. Hope that some day I’ll be able to and some day I’ll be able to play violin nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/09/musical-instruments-and-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/09/musical-instruments-and-me/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Choosing Workstation And Daily Tools</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a little freaky about choosing development environment, to work within. This includes the choice of OS, editor, local or remote etcetera. For some reason, I don’t want to work in local. I don’t know the exact reason behind it. But I like to work in the remote. If the connection sucks, that would be a problem, I know. But India is going towards big bandwidth millennia. So, I depend on the new promises for the long run. In Hyderabad, it’s now 40Mbps up to 150GB (after that 1Mbps) for Rs.641/- per month. I’m not saying it’s cheap. But, compared to the earlier days, like my first internet connection from BSNL &lt;em&gt;Broadband&lt;/em&gt; 1GB for Rs.250/- per month was a nightmare. Every two or three days, the cable got disconnected. And it was really a lucky day if I could get the lineman within 7 days to repair the disconnection. Somehow, I felt at that time that he did not wire the connection properly intentionally. To harass me. I don’t know what his benefit was in it. But I was sure. Eventually, I opted for the local cable operators for the internet connection. That was a &lt;em&gt;unlimited&lt;/em&gt; connection with advertised speed 512Kbps for, as far as I can remember Rs.600/- per month. With this connection, the wire didn’t disconnect every now and then. But, the connection really sucked. I at most got only 450-650Kbps. The only solace was that, great speed in downloading torrents. Around 10Mbps. Actually, the provider hosted some servers to peer for the torrents in the subscriber network. That also got disrupted after some inquiries from the Cyber Crime division of Kolkata police. In my office also the provided internet bandwidth was like a like very tight constipation. Downloading files more than 10MBs was blocked from the proxy. Yes, we had to use a proxy to connect to the internet. YouTube was allowed. But it was better to not watch it. Buffering made the experience real horrifying. I got the first taste of good internet after I came to Hyderabad. The city is good. Peaceful inhabitants. Cool weather. And good internet connection. And it got better. I started with the same plan, that I’m currently using. I started with FUP 10GB. Now it’s 150GB. For a reasonable internet surfer including viewing of reasonable quality videos, 150GB is more than enough. But If anyone likes best quality videos, they have higher plans also. Previously it was the reign of ACT. Now Hathway is also giving &lt;em&gt;unlimited&lt;/em&gt; internet with 50Mbps for only around Rs. 500/- (don’t know their exact packages). But I’m happy with ACT. If I require an unlimited connection, shall think about Hathway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written long completely off-topic. But internet connection is mandatory for working remotely. Currently, I’m working in a windows VM. I’m really liking working in this way. The main advantage is that the workstation does not need to be shut-down unless it becomes very slow. Does not need too much attention to maintaining the hardware, power etc. Anywhere I can just pick up where I left. Surely it has drawbacks. That without the internet, I’ll not be connected. But who nowadays works without the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I’m using &lt;em&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/em&gt; from Microsoft. It’s really a good editor. And with an array of plugins, it has become the default choice for me. And in-built NodeJs debugging is so awesome. Being a front-end developer, I don’t need much. But yes. I’ve installed Visual Studio, SQL Server in this VM. Don’t use them much. But they are there. If I need. I don’t know Java or Python or any compiled languages popular in the OpenSource community. I started my career with &lt;em&gt;C#&lt;/em&gt;. So, still now, got a soft corner for it. Probably if I am able to learn any other language, then will see. I know &lt;em&gt;JavaScript&lt;/em&gt; a little. But in my mind, that language is not for serious stuff. Until &lt;em&gt;JavaScript&lt;/em&gt; runs in a multi-threaded environment successfully, probably this mindset will continue to linger. Currently, I’m liking Golang. But for some reason could not gather enough enthusiasm to learn the language. Probably I’ll learn it in some time. &lt;em&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/em&gt; predicted that &lt;em&gt;Python&lt;/em&gt; is going to be the most popular language by 2019 at-least by the developer count. Actually, Python has acquired this much attention due to data science and machine learning. Python has become the de-facto choice for the new learners of data science and machine learning. And the language is quite easy to learn for new programmers. And in coming years machine learning along with the data science will appear as the most needed in any kind of business. So Python is becoming popular. One thing is there, Python is not compiled. But who cares. Most of the time the machine learning routines runs for days. After all, they are not like web apps. For web apps, I think Golang emerge as the first choice for creating backends. And &lt;em&gt;JavaScript&lt;/em&gt; will continue to reign the client side browser technologies with a monopoly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/08/choosing-workstation-and-daily-tools/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderuse.faith/2017/09/08/choosing-workstation-and-daily-tools/</guid>
        
        <category>100-words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
